<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reproducible Research on Stats &amp; bats</title>
    <link>/categories/reproducible-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reproducible Research on Stats &amp; bats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/reproducible-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A git workflow for ecologists</title>
      <link>/2017/08/git_workflow_ecologists/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/git_workflow_ecologists/</guid>
      <description>Git Target audience for this workflow Basic workflow Use case Principle  Branching workflow with pull requests Use case Principle Branch Pull request Conflicts  Flowcharts Rules for collaboration Exceptions    Git For those how don’t know git, it is a free and open source distributed version control system designed to handle everything from small to very large projects with speed and efficiency. I use git daily, including for this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating continuous coloured maps with osmplotr</title>
      <link>/2017/07/creating-maps-with-osmplotr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/creating-maps-with-osmplotr/</guid>
      <description>During useR!2017 I attended a talk by Mark Padgham titled Maps are data, so why no plot data on a map. In this blog post I will recreate the map from an earlier blogpost on estimating densities from a point pattern.
Let’s start by loading all required packages.
library(sp) library(MASS) library(dplyr) library(ggmap) library(osmplotr) I rearranged the code from the previous blog post in two chunks. The first chunk calculate the density and is required for both the ggmap and the osmplotr solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some things I learned about bookdown::gitbook</title>
      <link>/2017/06/bookdown-gitbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/bookdown-gitbook/</guid>
      <description>Bookdown is an R package that makes writing technical documents based on R much easier. One of the nice things is that you can create a corporate identity using LaTex styles for pdf output and Cascading Style Sheets for HTML output. I’m in the process of preparing such styles for the Research Institute for Nature and Forest.
Here are a few things that I figured out while testing a complex bookdown report.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>